grundfos.com 2013-09-13

# Privacy | Grundfos

At Grundfos we recognize that you may wish to maintain the confidentiality of the personal information you give online and we are aware that we are obliged to provide appropriate protection and responsible processing of all the personal information we receive.  

If you feel you cannot accept our privacy policy, we advise you not to use the Website.  

**Personal information**  
The term "Personal information" is used to describe any information that can be used to identify a physical person, including, although not restricted to, that person's first and last name, age, gender, private address or another physical address, E-mail address, or any other contact details, regardless of whether these refer to the person's home or workplace address.  

**What kinds of personal information do we gather and process?**  
As a rule, you can access the Website without letting us know who you are and without giving any personal information about yourself.  

However, Grundfos does need to register specific personal information in order to trade with you, and deliver news bulletins and other services.  

Grundfos registers and processes information about you when:

  * You enter information when you create or change your user account with us in order to use certain services, e.g. WebCAPS and Extranet.
  * You send us an enquiry or give us feedback 
  * and when you give any kind of personal information to us via the Website.

Grundfos registers only the personal information that is necessary in order to supply the service you have requested (e.g. your E-mail address or private address).  

In addition to the information you provide, your computer will automatically deliver data, which is registered at Grundfos so that we can analyse how users use the Website. To do this we use Google Analytics and Adobe Digital Marketing Suite.  

Grundfos never receives personal information about users of our Website from a third party.  

Grundfos does not store information on methods of payment, such as debit card numbers, bank account numbers, or similar.

**Who do we disclose personal information to?**  
Personal information entered on the Website is disclosed only to:

  * companies in the Grundfos Group
  * carefully selected third parties entrusted to use your personal information in order to deliver the goods or services you have ordered.

Grundfos only discloses personal information in accordance with applicable legislation.  

To develop and improve the Website, we gather statistical data on how users use the site. The statistical data is used only in its accumulated form, e.g. to see which pages and browsers are most frequently used by our users.  

Grundfos uses Google Analytics, Adobe Digital Marketing Suite and Globase to register website visitor data and discloses the IP addresses in the data to Google Analytics, Adobe Digital Marketing Suite and Globase.  

Google Analytics, Adobe Digital Marketing Suite and Globase may also disclose the data to a third party where this is legally required, or to a third party working for them.  

With the exception of the above, Grundfos does not disclose data relating to the individual user and how he/she uses the services provided on our website.  

**How do we store your personal information?**  
Personal information is stored on servers in Denmark and USA. Some personal information is managed by a third party (data processor), which stores and processes personal information on Grundfos' behalf in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable legislation relating to the protection of personal information.

We store personal information only for as long as this is necessary for the above-mentioned purposes.  

**Access to the information**  
You can change your account details and areas of interest at any time, and, if you wish, you can request that we contact you in connection with an offer on a product or service or to unsubscribe from newsletters.  

We can inform you which information we have registered about you and you are entitled to object to our registering your personal information. If you wish to receive information about which of your personal information we process or if you wish to object to our processing your personal information, [contact us here](http://www.grundfos.com/nav/contact.html#grundfos_corporation).

**Contact, amendments and updates to the privacy policy**  
Grundfos is obliged at any time to meet legislative requirements pertaining to the protection of personal privacy. At the top of our privacy policy, you can always see when the policy was last updated.  

If you have any questions or comments related to our privacy policy or how we use your personal information, [contact us here](http://www.grundfos.com/nav/contact.html#grundfos_corporation).
